Inna Widener

iwide2019@gmail.com | (469) 346-6489 | Dallas, TX 75204

Github: https://github.com/iwidener | Website: https://iwidener.github.io/Portfolio/

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/inna-w

Web Developer

Full Stack Web Developer with significant experience in Linguistics and Educational fields within international and domestic companies. Excited to write the code, develop responsive websites as well as deliver outstanding and functional web experiences. Earned a certificate in Web Development through Southern Methodist University. Positioned to contribute to teamwork with a personal passion for the details, critical thinking and excellent communication skills. Disciplined to do work with minimum supervision.

Technical Skills

Languages/Tools: HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, Express, Handlebars.js, Sequelize, MongoDB

Projects

Hey Y'all! https://github.com/iwidener | https://kayla8693.github.io/classroom-self-checkin

- Classroom self check-in is an application designed for teachers to keep a track of students' attendance and improve a class performance.
- Brainstormed and initiated an idea for the team project.
- Responsible for the weather/UVI APIs, time/clock, badge, favicon, background, sticky footer.
- Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Moment.js, Ajax, APIs

Friendly https://immense-garden-32852.herokuapp.com/

- Friends by interests is an application to help the users connecting with each other online and sharing their common interests.
- Created a repository in GitHub and application deployment in Heroku.
- Responsible for adding two libraries to the project: Socket.IO and cdnis.
- Explored the possibility of improving the project by adding Vonage or Twilio in the future.
- Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Javascript, Handlebars.js, Express, Node.js, Passport, bcryptjs, Travis CI, Eslint, Skeleton-cdnjs.com, Socket.IO, MySQL, Sequelize, Heroku, JAWSDB

Experience

Substitute Teacher Dallas Independent School District

2015 – Present

Dallas, TX

- Instruct and supervise the students in elementary, middle, and high schools according to the lesson plans and DISD policies.
- Committed to make the young adults be responsible.

Substitute Teacher/Proctor Vientiane International School

2012 - 2014

Vientiane, Laos

- Instructed and supervised the students in elementary, middle, and high schools according to the lesson plans and school policies. Successfully supported the high standards of this international school and maintained the professional relations with other teachers.
- Supervised the IB exams in Grade 12. There were no policy violations.
- Key Accomplishments: Recommendation letter from Director of Vientiane International School in Laos dated November 2014.

CAE (Cleared American Escort)

2011-2012

BL Harbert International/New US Embassy Construction Project Monrovia, Liberia

- Directed and escorted the local employees in the secured areas of the jobsite.
- Supervised the cleaning crew. Guided and helped the local people to do the work according to the jobsite requirements with no violations recorded.

Substitute Teacher

2011 – 2011

International Community School

Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

• Instructed and supervised the students in elementary, middle, and high schools according to the lesson plans and school policies.

CAE and Warehouseman

2010-2011

BL Harbert International/New US Embassy Construction Project Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

- Directed and escorted the local employees in the secured areas of the jobsite.
- Organized and did inventory of the secured construction materials.

GSO Assistant

2008 – 2009

US Embassy

Brazzaville, RC

- Coordinated the work of different sections in the General Services Office according to the US Embassy policies and ensured the timely submissions/compliance of standards.
- Key Accomplishments: Certificate of Appreciation for outstanding contribution in improving GSO Motorpool Services at US Embassy in Brazzaville, Republic of Congo, dated 01/23/2009.

Education

Full Stack Bootcamp Certificate:

currently earning the certificate at SMU Boot Camp, Dallas, TX

Bachelor of Arts Degree: Kyiv State Linguistic University, Kyiv, Ukraine

Major: English as a Foreign Language and English Literature with a minor in French